Guide to the David Dellinger Papers TAM.252
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
David Dellinger Papers
circa 1915-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Dellinger, David T., 1915-2004
Yale University
Peterson, Elizabeth
Akst, Daniel
TAM.252
14.5 Linear Feet in 14 record cartons and 1 manuscript box
David Dellinger (1915-2004) was a peace activist, most famously known as a member of the Chicago Seven. The collection includes correspondence, periodicals, pamphlets, notebooks, writings, newsletters, photographs, teaching materials, and other ephemera. The collection mostly contains materials related to his activism after the Chicago Seven trial up until about 1999, including planning materials for antiwar fasts, protests, and demonstrations against wars, the Middle East conflict, and conflict in South America and Libya.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Original order has been maintained.
Biographical Note
David Dellinger (1915-2004) is most remembered for his role as the oldest defendant in the 1969 Chicago Seven trial, in which anti-Vietnam War activists were charged with conspiring to disrupt the 1968 Democratic National Convention. Yet he was a lifelong peace activist and continued to be involved in peace activism in the 1990s. Additionally, Dellinger was the editor of two leftist publications, Liberation (1956-1977) and Seven Days (1975-1980). In 1980 he and his family moved to Vermont, where he taught and wrote his memoir From Yale to Jail: The Life Story of a Moral Dissenter (1993). In addition to his autobiography, he wrote ''Revolutionary Nonviolence'' (1971), ''More Power Than We Know'' (1975), and ''Vietnam Revisited'' (1986).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were possibly transferred from Yale University in circa 2001; one linear feet of files and video tapes (Box 12) were transferred from Yale University Library to Tamiment in 2007. Eleven linear feet of materials from David Dellinger and Elizabeth Peterson (his wife) were most likely donated to Tamiment in circa 1999. The accession number associated with this collection is 2007.022. In 2019, Daniel Akst donated an accretion of two boxes; the accession number associated with this gift is 2019.080.
Related Archival Materials
Leonard Weinglass (TAM 584)
Scope and Contents
This collection is made up of the personal papers of David Dellinger, a peace activist and member of the Chicago Seven and includes correspondence, periodicals, pamphlets, notebooks, writings, newsletters, photographs, teaching materials, and other ephemera. The collection mostly contains materials related to his activism from the 1960s to about 1999, including planning materials for antiwar fasts, protests, and demonstrations against wars, the Middle East conflict, and conflict in South America and Libya or focuses on his life in Vermont in the 1980s and 1990s. The collection also includes materials related to the publication of his book, From Yale to Jail: The Life Story of a Moral Dissenter and the book tour related to it. There is a significant amount of correspondence, including personal letters, correspondence related to the publication and fundraising of Seven Days magazine, and with prisoners and others. There is some materials related to the Chicago Seven case, including court proceedings and contempt trials. While there is not much pertaining to the Chicago Seven trial, this collection is a rich resource for researchers interested in social justice and peace movements in Vermont in the 1980s and 1990s as well as Dellinger's life after the trial that made him famous.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Anti-war demonstrations.; Peace movements -- United States.; Chicago Seven Trial, Chicago, Ill., 1969-1970.; Yale University; Peterson, Elizabeth; Akst, Daniel
- $ [Addresses], 589889 (Box 1)
- Enlisted Times, 589890 (Box 1)
- Take [Palestine Israeli Conflict], Mar-Apr 1980; 589891 (Box 1)
- Business Information, 1980; 589892 (Box 1)
- [Seven Days advertising], undated; 589893 (Box 1)
- INC [Institute for New Communications] Members, circa 1978; 589894 (Box 1)
- Dellinger, 1978; 589895 (Box 1)
- Letters - Answer, 1980; 589896 (Box 1)
- Pledges, 1979; 589897 (Box 1)
- Refinancing, Dec 1978; 589898 (Box 1)
- Cole, William, 589899 (Box 1)
- Collins, Judy, 589900 (Box 1)
- Connolly, John and Carol (Minn.), 589901 (Box 1)
- Engelhardt, Sophie (Mass.), 589902 (Box 1)
- Erdman, Abigail (Mass.), 589903 (Box 1)
- Evans, Hermene, 589904 (Box 1)
- Factor, Max (Cal.), 589905 (Box 1)
- Falk, Dick and Florence (NJ), 589906 (Box 1)
- Feiffer, Jules (NY), 589907 (Box 1)
- Ferry, Ping and Carol (NY), 589908 (Box 1)
- Fischman, Mr. and Mrs. Bernard, 589909 (Box 1)
- Freed, Frank (Chicago), 589910 (Box 1)
- Friedkin, Wm, 589911 (Box 1)
- Fund for Peace (NY), 589912 (Box 1)
- Gamwell, Chris (Rockefeller Family Trust), 589913 (Box 1)
- Gendler, Everett and Mary (Mass.), 589914 (Box 1)
- Gilbert, Sam (Cal.), 589915 (Box 1)
- Ginsberg, Allen (NY-Cal.), 589916 (Box 1)
- Golden, Sybil (NY), 589917 (Box 1)
- Goodman, Carolyn (NY), 589918 (Box 1)
- Goodwin, Richard (DC), 589919 (Box 1)
- Jack Gray (Oregon), 589920 (Box 1)
- Cowan, Geoff and Aileen Adams, 589921 (Box 1)
- Cowan, Paul and Rachel, 589922 (Box 1)
- Crocker, David (Mass.), 589923 (Box 1)
- Crosby, Harriet, 589924 (Box 1)
- Crowley, Joseph (New Haven, Conn.), 589925 (Box 1)
- Alida Davidson (Cal.), 589926 (Box 1)
- Kinoy, Susan (NY), 589927 (Box 1)
- Knight, Charles (MA), 589928 (Box 1)
- Dayton, Mark (DC), 589929 (Box 1)
- Doctorow, Ed, 589930 (Box 1)
- Dowd, Doug (Cal.), 589931 (Box 1)
- Dulaney, Peggy and Quattrone, David (Mass.), 589932 (Box 1)
- Duskin, Alvin and Sarah (Cal.), 589933 (Box 1)
- Dutcher, Cornelius and Barbara (Cal.), 589934 (Box 1)
- Eldridge, Don (Cal.), 589935 (Box 1)
- Ellsberg, Dan (Cal.), 589936 (Box 1)
- Gregory, Dick (Mass.), 589937 (Box 1)
- Grossman, Richard (NY), 589938 (Box 1)
- Nancy/Sam Gruber (Conn.), 589939 (Box 1)
- Grumman, Sterling G. - Deceased (Mass.), 589940 (Box 1)
- Harburg, E.Y. (NY), 589941 (Box 1)
- Harnick, Sheldon (NY), 589942 (Box 1)
- Harris, Fred and LaDona, 589943 (Box 1)
- Harris, King (Cal.), 589944 (Box 1)
- Hartgen, Stephen, 589945 (Box 1)
- Haussamen, Carol (NY), 589946 (Box 1)
- Clarence Heller, 589947 (Box 1)
- Edward S. Herman (Penn.), 589948 (Box 1)
- Hess, Anne Helen and Wiehoff, Dale (Wis.), 589949 (Box 1)
- Hixon, Alexander (NY), 589950 (Box 1)
- Hoagland, Ralph (Mass.), 589951 (Box 1)
- Hochschild, Adam (Cal.), 589952 (Box 1)
- Hoffman, Dustin (NY), 589953 (Box 1)
- Gene Hoffman, 589954 (Box 1)
- Hoffman, Hallock, 589955 (Box 1)
- Hoffman, Lyla (Mrs.) (NY), 589956 (Box 1)
- Hogle, George (Cal.), 589957 (Box 1)
- Hohler, Bob (Vermont), 589958 (Box 1)
- Monica Hollstein, 589959 (Box 1)
- Holman, Dr. and Mrs. Halsted (Cal.), 589960 (Box 1)
- Honig, Louis (Cal.), 589961 (Box 1)
- Victor Honig (Cal.), 589962 (Box 1)
- Hormel, Gordon (Cal.), 589963 (Box 1)
- Horowitz, Garry (Cal.), 589964 (Box 1)
- Horowitz, Irving L. (NJ), 589965 (Box 1)
- Hurwich, Rudy (Cal.), 589966 (Box 1)
- IPS, 589967 (Box 1)
- Janov, Arthur (Cal.), 589968 (Box 1)
- Janss, Ed (Cal.-NY), 589969 (Box 1)
- Janss, Larry (Cal.), 589970 (Box 1)
- Jenkins, Mrs. James H, 589971 (Box 1)
- Kaldenbach, Bob, 589972 (Box 1)
- Katz, Charles (Cal.), 589973 (Box 1)
- Kazan, Elia, 589974 (Box 1)
- Kendall, Anne (Mass.), 589975 (Box 1)
- Spencer Kinnard, 589976 (Box 1)
- Kennedy, Michael (Cal.), 589977 (Box 1)
- Kepler, Roy (Cal.), 589978 (Box 1)
- Lamb, Edward (Ohio), 589979 (Box 1)
- Lamont, Corliss (NY), 589980 (Box 1)
- Lang, Daniel (NY), 589981 (Box 1)
- Laucks, Irving, 589982 (Box 1)
- Berla Langston (NY), 589983 (Box 1)
- Lear, Norman (Cal.), 589984 (Box 1)
- Lefcourt, Bob (NY), 589985 (Box 1)
- Lens, Sid (Ill.), 589986 (Box 1)
- Lerman, Omar K., 589987 (Box 1)
- Levinson Foundation - Sidney Shapiro (Mass.), 589988 (Box 1)
- Lewis, Alfred Baker (Conn.), 589989 (Box 1)
- Lewis, Salim (NY), 589990 (Box 1)
- Liben, Judith (Mass.), 589991 (Box 1)
- Lieben, Sam (NJ), 589992 (Box 1)
- Lifton, Bob and Betty Jean (NY), 589993 (Box 1)
- Lloyd, William B Jr. (Ill.), 589994 (Box 1)
- Lockwood, Ted (NH), 589995 (Box 1)
- Lumet, Gail and Sidney (NY), 589996 (Box 1)
- Josh Mailman, 589997 (Box 1)
- Lown, Bernard and Louise, 589998 (Box 1)
- McCormack, Win, 589999 (Box 1)
- McGee, Vinnie (NY), 590000 (Box 1)
- McCue, M and M Allen (Maine), 590001 (Box 1)
- MacLaine, Shirley, 590002 (Box 1)
- Shirley Magidson, 590003 (Box 1)
- Norman Mailer, 590004 (Box 1)
- Melnick, Dan (Cal.), 590005 (Box 1)
- Merer, Todd (Cal.), 590006 (Box 1)
- Meynet, Maryanne Mott, 590007 (Box 1)
- Howard Koch, 590008 (Box 1)
- Middle East, 590009 (Box 1)
- Book - Teenagers, 590010 (Box 1)
- Early Chapter From Yale to Jail, 590011 (Box 1)
- Ron Kovic, 590012 (Box 1)
- [Loose Seven Days Materials], 590013 (Box 1)
- [Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors packet], 1998; 590014 (Box 2)
- FOR [Fellowship of Reconciliation], 1998; 590015 (Box 2)
- Bio Photos on 2 [two folders], 1989-1998; 590016 (Box 2)
- Green Mountain Popular Education Center, 1995-1997; 590017 (Box 2)
- Book Contracts, 590018 (Box 2)
- EarthPeace International Film Festival, 1992; 590019 (Box 2)
- Income and Expenses, 590020 (Box 2)
- Bio [two folders], 1976-1998; 590021 (Box 2)
- Bill Worthy, 590022 (Box 2)
- Ironsides et al, 590023 (Box 2)
- Boston Initiative - NCIPA [National Committee for Independent Political Action]- New, 1991-1993; 590024 (Box 2)
- Dale Byam [two folders], 1987-1998; 590025 (Box 2)
- IPPN [Independent Progressive Politics Network], 1998-1999; 590026 (Box 2)
- Kent State University Press, 1996-1998; 590027 (Box 2)
- Colorado et al, 590028 (Box 2)
- "Columbus Day" Fasts and Protests, 1997-1999; 590029 (Box 2)
- Frank Lovell, 590030 (Box 2)
- Bruderhof, 590031 (Box 2)
- Buddhism, 590032 (Box 2)
- Anarchism, 590033 (Box 2)
- Auto - Misc., 590034 (Box 3)
- Thalberg, Irving (Ill.), 590035 (Box 3)
- Thorne, John (Cal.), 590036 (Box 3)
- Tishman, John I., 590037 (Box 3)
- Vandenheuvel, Jean (NY), 590038 (Box 3)
- Wallace, Henry (KY), 590039 (Box 3)
- Wallman, Joshua (NY), 590040 (Box 3)
- Wallis, Victor (Ind.), 590041 (Box 3)
- Washburn, Michael (NY), 590042 (Box 3)
- Milgrim, Lorna (NJ), 590043 (Box 3)
- Arthur Miller (CT), 590044 (Box 3)
- Miller, Joe (PA), 590045 (Box 3)
- Miller, Maya (Nev.), 590046 (Box 3)
- Miller, Merle (NY), 590047 (Box 3)
- Milwe, Bea (Conn.), 590048 (Box 3)
- Monroe, Mona P. (NY), 590049 (Box 3)
- Moore, Paul (Bishop), 590050 (Box 3)
- Moore, Paul Jr. (OR), 590051 (Box 3)
- Mott, Stewart, 590052 (Box 3)
- Mustone, Amelia and John, 590053 (Box 3)
- Newman, Jim (Calif.), 590054 (Box 3)
- Newman, Stanley (Cal.), 590055 (Box 3)
- New World Foundation - David Ramage, 590056 (Box 3)
- Niles, Henry (MD), 590057 (Box 3)
- Norman, Andy (The Norman Foundation), 590058 (Box 3)
- Dan Noyes, 590059 (Box 3)
- O'Brien, Tomy (Minn.), 590060 (Box 3)
- Bertell Ollman (NY), 590061 (Box 3)
- Bicycle Trip, 1951; 590062 (Box 3)
- Special Correspondents, 1986-1996; 590063 (Box 3)
- Fast [People's Fast for Justice], 1995; 590064 (Box 3)
- Permissions for Book, 590065 (Box 3)
- Trust for Nonviolent Revolution, 590066 (Box 3)
- Book Promotion, 590067 (Box 3)
- Tour Finances, 590068 (Box 3)
- Fast - Key materials, 1994; 590069 (Box 3)
- Fast, 1994; 590071 (Box 3)
- Fast, Oct 1-12, 1993; 590070 (Box 3)
- Book Reviews and Tour Articles, 590072 (Box 3)
- McDonough, 590073 (Box 3)
- Fast, 1992; 590074 (Box 3)
- Book Promotion, 590075 (Box 3)
- Auto Materials, 590076 (Box 3)
- Miami Conventions, 590077 (Box 3)
- Puerto Rico, 590078 (Box 4)
- Yale Seminar, 1977; 590079 (Box 4)
- Tour, 590080 (Box 4)
- [12 Loose Notebooks], 590081 (Box 4)
- [Boxed Notebooks], 590082 (Box 4)
- Leahy, 590083 (Box 4)
- International League - Rights and Liberation of All Peoples, 590084 (Box 4)
- Gorin Letters, 590085 (Box 4)
- Guatemala, 590086 (Box 4)
- Gorin Book, 590087 (Box 4)
- Dachine, 590088 (Box 4)
- Constitution, 590089 (Box 4)
- Rainbow, 590090 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1987; 590092 (Box 4)
- Essays on Nonviolent Force Book OLP, 1989-1992; 590091 (Box 4)
- Dellinger, 590093 (Box 4)
- ADP [Adult Degree Program], 590094 (Box 4)
- Brian, 590095 (Box 4)
- [Loose Writings], 590096 (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1989; 590097 (Box 5)
- Middle East, 590098 (Box 5)
- Zeta Shopts, 590099 (Box 5)
- Hoffman - Interviews, 590100 (Box 5)
- Prison - Jefferson Dorsey's County Row, 590101 (Box 5)
- Geo. Wald et al, 590102 (Box 5)
- Chomsky Article, 590103 (Box 5)
- NBAU [No Business as Usual!], 1988; 590104 (Box 5)
- Disarmament Book Correspondence, 590105 (Box 5)
- Historical Materials Liberation Spring Mobil[ization Committee to End the War in Vietnam]/Seven Days, 1988; 590106 (Box 5)
- Speak Out!, 590107 (Box 5)
- Toward Freedom - Changing Editor, 590108 (Box 5)
- Wild Bill Steyert Jr., 1998-1999; 590109 (Box 5)
- Jun 18-20, Jun 18-20, 1983; 590110 (Box 5)
- 50th Anniversary, 590111 (Box 5)
- European Trip, Mother Jones, 1983; 590112 (Box 5)
- John Born Albury, 590113 (Box 5)
- Albert Chang, 590114 (Box 5)
- Martin Sheen, 590115 (Box 5)
- Luciano, Lenny and Tasha, 590116 (Box 5)
- Steyert and Rev. Schupp, 590117 (Box 5)
- Paul Scavitto, 590118 (Box 5)
- Library or Bookstore, 590119 (Box 5)
- Media Contacts, 590120 (Box 5)
- Nicaragua, 590121 (Box 5)
- Local, 590122 (Box 5)
- Peacework, 590123 (Box 5)
- Letters about Book or Tour, 590124 (Box 6)
- Vermont College - Evaluations, 590125 (Box 6)
- Random House, 590126 (Box 6)
- Katherine Power, 590127 (Box 6)
- Prisons (VT), 590128 (Box 6)
- Prisons, 590129 (Box 6)
- VVAW [Vietnam Veterans Against the War] and VEP [Veterans Education Project], 1992; 590130 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1994; 590131 (Box 6)
- More Letters about Books or Tour, 590132 (Box 6)
- Flower Project, Oct 1967; 590133 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1995; 590134 (Box 6)
- UCP [University Conversion Project], 590135 (Box 6)
- Terrorism, 590136 (Box 6)
- Vietnam Walk, 590137 (Box 6)
- Sanders Campaign, 1986; 590138 (Box 6)
- Toronto, Jun 1988; 590139 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1996-1997; 590140 (Box 6)
- More Correspondence, 1970-1972; 590141 (Box 6)
- White Ship, 590142 (Box 7)
- HBO, 1987; 590143 (Box 7)
- Young Authors, 590144 (Box 7)
- Trial - Ellsberg, 1987; 590145 (Box 7)
- El Salvador Action, Oct 17, 1988; 590146 (Box 7)
- Possible for Appendix and Illustrations, 590147 (Box 7)
- Chicago 5 and 11, 590148 (Box 7)
- Chicago, 1996; 590149 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1988; 590150 (Box 7)
- Other Correspondence, 1981-1983; 590151 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1990; 590152 (Box 7)
- Chicago '68 Miscellany, 590153 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1988-1989; 590154 (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1980-1987; 590155 (Box 7)
- Chicago '68 + 20, 590156 (Box 7)
- Chicago, 1996; 590157 (Box 7)
- "The Sixties" Conference, 1996; 590158 (Box 7)
- Copy 3 Hist. Background, 590159 (Box 7)
- Talk Materials, 590160 (Box 7)
- Correspondence varied in year and purpose, 590161 (Box 7)
- TF [Toward Freedom, Inc.] Meeting, 1996-1997; 590162 (Box 8)
- Correspondence - Old, 1970; 590163 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1989-1990; 590164 (Box 8)
- Historical Background Copy One, 590165 (Box 8)
- Palevsky, Joan (Cal.), 590166 (Box 8)
- Palevsky, Max (Cal.), 590167 (Box 8)
- Perry, Eleanor (NY), 590168 (Box 8)
- Lawrence Phillips (NYC), 590169 (Box 8)
- Piel, Gerald (NY), 590170 (Box 8)
- Pillsbury, Charles (CT), 590171 (Box 8)
- Pillsbury, George (MA), 590172 (Box 8)
- Pillsbury, Sarah, 590173 (Box 8)
- Plimpton, Oakes (Mass.), 590174 (Box 8)
- Lenny Brown, 590175 (Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1991; 590176 (Box 8)
- ADP [Adult Degree Program] - Goddard, 1970s; 590177 (Box 8)
- Contempt Trial, 1973; 590178 (Box 8)
- [Loose Seven Days Magazine materials and correspondence], 1970s; 590179 (Box 8)
- Watts, Fay Bennett (NY), 590180 (Box 8)
- POW's, 590181 (Box 8)
- Weber, Marian (Cal.), 590182 (Box 8)
- Weiss, Cora and Peter (NY), 590183 (Box 8)
- Stanley A. Weiss (Boston), 590184 (Box 8)
- Wexler, Haskell (Cal.), 590185 (Box 8)
- Sam Wiener, 590186 (Box 8)
- Willens, Harold (Cal.), 590187 (Box 8)
- Jon Wolman, 590188 (Box 8)
- Cooks, Stony and Young, Andy (DC), 590189 (Box 8)
- Zeigler, Bea and Irv (Cal.), 590190 (Box 8)
- Louis, Zemel (Conn.), 590191 (Box 8)
- Zevin, Robert, 590192 (Box 8)
- Sullivan, Nancy (Mass.), 590193 (Box 8)
- Straus, Peter R. (NY), 590194 (Box 8)
- Stuart, Lyle, 590195 (Box 8)
- Nancy Sullivan, 590196 (Box 8)
- Temkin, Florence, 590197 (Box 8)
- Terkel, Studs and Ida (Ill.), 590198 (Box 8)
- Sherman, Gordon (Cal.), 590199 (Box 8)
- Sontag, Susan (NY), 590200 (Box 8)
- So End Press, 590201 (Box 8)
- Spain, Dr. David and Ruth (NY), 590202 (Box 8)
- Sperber, Larry (Cal.), 590203 (Box 8)
- Paul and Ann Sperry (NYC), 590204 (Box 8)
- Spock, Benjamin, 590205 (Box 8)
- Stanton, David (Cal.), 590206 (Box 8)
- Starfield, Bess and Harry (NY), 590207 (Box 8)
- Steinem, Gloria (NY), 590208 (Box 8)
- Stoller, Robert (CA), 590209 (Box 8)
- Stone, I.F. (DC), 590210 (Box 8)
- Stover, Robert and Mrs. (NY), 590211 (Box 8)
- Rubin, Miles (NY), 590212 (Box 8)
- Tom Wicker, 590213 (Box 8)
- Rubin, Sam (NY), 590214 (Box 8)
- Rubin, Vera (NY), 590215 (Box 8)
- Russell, M.H. (Cal.), 590216 (Box 8)
- Ryerson, Edward (Mass.), 590217 (Box 8)
- Sandperl, Ira (Cal.), 590218 (Box 8)
- Sayre, Bill (Mass.), 590219 (Box 8)
- Schneider, Bert (Cal.), 590220 (Box 8)
- Seeger, Pete (NY), 590221 (Box 8)
- Semrad, Joseph (Okla.), 590222 (Box 8)
- Sennett, William (CF In These Times), 590223 (Box 8)
- Sheerer, Benjamin (Handles Anonymous Donation), 590224 (Box 8)
- Sheinbaum, Stanley (Cal.), 590225 (Box 8)
- Violent Groups on Left, 590226 (Box 8)
- Plunkett, Michael (Cal.), 590227 (Box 8)
- Power, Taryn (Italy), 590228 (Box 8)
- Powsner, Robert (Cal.), 590229 (Box 8)
- Price, Paton and Tilly, 590230 (Box 8)
- Ram Dass (NH), 590231 (Box 8)
- Rapoport, Bernard, 590232 (Box 8)
- Raskin, Marcus, 590233 (Box 8)
- Rigler, Lloyd (Cal.), 590234 (Box 8)
- Keith Roberts (S.F.C.A.), 590235 (Box 8)
- Rockefeller, Abby (Mass.), 590236 (Box 8)
- Rogers, Henry Gibbs (NY), 590237 (Box 8)
- Frank Roosevelt, 590238 (Box 8)
- Rosenbaum, Judy (Mass.), 590239 (Box 8)
- Dan Rothenberg, Boston, 590240 (Box 8)
- No. Cty Coalition - Crisis Relocation [Planning], 590241 (Box 8)
- Toward Freedom, 1987-1991; 590242 (Box 8)
- War Crimes Tribunal, 590243 (Box 8)
- International Lists, 590244 (Box 9)
- Martin Luther King Jr., 590245 (Box 9)
- Ben and Jerry's Foundation, 590246 (Box 9)
- Hardwick Peace and Justice Center, 590247 (Box 9)
- International, 590248 (Box 9)
- Randy Kehler, Betsy Corner, 590249 (Box 9)
- Allen Ginsberg, 590250 (Box 9)
- Nonviolent Warrior Group, 590251 (Box 9)
- James Tracy, Book and Hotchkiss, 1994; 590252 (Box 9)
- Jim Rayle, 590253 (Box 9)
- PVA [Progressive Vermont Alliance], 1992; 590254 (Box 9)
- Bill Kunstler, 590255 (Box 9)
- Current Vietnam, 590256 (Box 9)
- Correspondence - Copies, 590257 (Box 9)
- Bill Worthy, 590258 (Box 9)
- Doubleday, 590259 (Box 9)
- Disarmament Magazine, 590260 (Box 9)
- (Family) Correspondence, 590261 (Box 9)
- Correspondence - Special, 590262 (Box 9)
- Liberation, 590263 (Box 9)
- Prisoners, 590264 (Box 9)
- Bob Brown, 590265 (Box 9)
- Old Leaflets - People's Peace Now, 1951; 590266 (Box 9)
- Winooski 44, 1984; 590267 (Box 9)
- Contempt, 590268 (Box 9)
- Prisoner Correspondence, 590269 (Box 9)
- POW's, 590270 (Box 9)
- Interviews, 590271 (Box 10)
- Domestic Lists - Out of Date, 590272 (Box 10)
- Naropa [Institute], 1994; 590273 (Box 10)
- Muste Grant, 590274 (Box 10)
- Coalition for Justice and Peace in the Middle East, 1980-1981; 590275 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1977-1978; 590276 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1974-1975; 590277 (Box 10)
- Letters et al, Trip-Vietnam, China, Moscow, 1966; 590278 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1981-1983; 590279 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1970-1972; 590280 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1970-1972; 590281 (Box 10)
- More Correspondence, 1967-1968; 590282 (Box 10)
- From Auschwitz to Hiroshima, 1995-1996; 590283 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1987; 590284 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1980s; 590285 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1992-1993; 590286 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, 1971; 590287 (Box 11)
- Pat Morris, 590288 (Box 11)
- Correspondence, circa 1986; 590289 (Box 11)
- Nicaragua, 590290 (Box 11)
- Current Correspondence, 1972; 590291 (Box 11)
- Correspondence, 1984; 590292 (Box 11)
- Correspondence, 1970-1972; 590293 (Box 11)
- Correspondence, 1967-1968; 590294 (Box 11)
- Libya, 1992; 590295 (Box 11)
- Libya, 590296 (Box 11)
- Memo - Libya, Grand Jury, 590297 (Box 11)
- Toward Freedom, 1991; 590298 (Box 11)
- Correspondence, 1993; 590299 (Box 11)
- More Correspondence, 1970-1972; 590300 (Box 11)
- Conspiracy Trials, 590310 (Box 12)
- Committee for Huey Newton, 1974-1976; 590311 (Box 12)
- Vietnam, 590309 (Box 12)
- [Loose Periodicals and Court Documents], 1968-1970; 590312 (Box 12)
- NBC Sunday Marv Davidov and Dave Dellinger [VHS], 590301 (Box 12)
- Sweetser Lecture Series in Wakefield, MA [VHS], 1994; 590302 (Box 12)
- CBS News Productions, TLC Legends, The Chicago Seven: America on Trial [VHS], 590303 (Box 12)
- Celebration of Conscience Interview with Dave Dellinger and Norm Smith, filmed by Dennis Willert [VHS], 1990; 590304 (Box 12)
- Dellinger Interview (Channel 3 News-Champaign) (For Steve Sato and Dave Dellinger) [VHS], 590305 (Box 12)
- Minnesota Public Television Marv Davidov Interview, 590306 (Box 12)
- Dave Dellinger: Peace Activist and Author of "From Yale to Jail: Hope for the Nineties World Fellowship Center, Conway, New Hampshire [VHS], 1993; 590307 (Box 12)
- Quincentennial Interfaith Pilgrimage for Peace and Life [VHS], 590308 (Box 12)
- 2019 Accretion – Research Files and Ephemera; Correspondence; Manuscripts and Drafts for Books, Plays, and Articles; Notebooks and Notes; Photographs; Financial Materials, 1965-1996 (Box 13)
- 2019 Accretion – Manuscripts and Drafts for Books, Speeches, Poems, etc.; Research Files and Ephemera; Correspondence; Notes and Notebooks; Financial Materials, 1936-1940, 1950-1980, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Box 15)